Finding Aid for Muschenheim, William. Architectural drawings and papers. 1925-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Job 71, New York World's Fair
    - [New York World's Fair (1939-1940). America At Home. Parents' retreat room]
      - Drawings, #.01599-.01618 February-April, 1940
        - [Study of exhibit room 12 showing interior perspective]., NYDA.1986.004.01606; Stat in negative.
        - [Study of exhibit room 12 showing interior perspective], NYDA.1986.004.01607
          (Drawing has been splattered with blue paint.)
        - [Sketch of exhibit room 12 showing interior perspective]., NYDA.1986.004.01608
        - [Study of exhibit room 12 showing interior perspective with shading, without furnishings]., NYDA.1986.004.01609
        - [Study of exhibit room showing interior perspective without furnishing]., NYDA.1986.004.01610
        - [Sketch of exhibit room 12 showing interior perspective without furnishings]., NYDA.1986.004.01611
        - [Study of exhibit room 12 showing a plan with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01612
          (Ink on tracing paper.)
        - [Study of exhibit room 12 showing a plan with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01613
        - [Sketch of exhibit room 12 showing a plan with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01614
        - [Sketch of exhibit room 12 showing a plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01615
        - Exhibit room [12] plan and elevs. [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2, 4/4/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01616
        - Isometric drawings of desk [and] dressing table [and oblique view, plan, and elevations of loudspeaker, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3, 4/12/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01617
        - Isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and elevations of day-bed [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4, 4/19/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01618
      - Papers
        - archival: (Box A10, Folder 71-1)
          (fabric samples, 2 pages of notes, I pamphlet, 1 site plan[?])
        - archival: correspondence. (Box A10, Folder 71-2)
          (Corresponded with: Medason Inc. Furniture, The Formica Insulation Company, Louise Bonney Leicester (Director of "America at Home"), Shepard Vogelgesand, Zermann-Acme Woodworking Corp., Kurt Versen Company (lighting), Pola Stout Fabrics, and others.)
  - Job 72, Robert D. Howard
    - Robert D. Howard residence
      - Drawings, #.01619-.01634 August-November, 1940, 16 sheets: various media; or smaller 64 x 85 cm.; 25-1/4 x 33-1/2 inches
        This set consists of 9 pencil on tracing paper, 4 pencil with pastel on tracing paper, and 3 pencil on paper.
        - Guest bath and dress. rm. [showing a plan with notes]: Drawing 1 8/8/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01619
        - Plan, [north exterior] elev. and sect. [of] guest bath and dress rm. [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1-A 08/14/1940 revised, 08/21/1940, 09/11/1940, 9/24/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01620
        - Plan, [exterior] elev. and sect. of west porch [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2 8/15/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01621
        - [1st fl. guest bath showing interior elevations and reflected ceiling plan; dr. rm. showing interior elevations and plan of 2nd fl. bath, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3 08/23/1940 rev., 9/9/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01622
        - Interior dt'ls [of] guest bath [showing sect's thru windows, glass shelves, sliding door and glass screen, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 09/16/1940 revised, 9/24/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01623
        - Int. elevs. [of] 2nd fl. bath [with a F.S.D. at door jamb and at floor, and a reflected ceiling plan, with notes]: Drawing 5 10/14/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01624
        - Plan, [exterior] elev. and dt'ls. of trellis [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 6 11/28/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01625
        - [Study of exterior perspective showing "v" support of the trellis], NYDA.1986.004.01626
        - [Study of exterior perspective showing extended concrete block wall with square perforations], NYDA.1986.004.01627
        - [Study of exterior perspective showing extended concrete block wall with square perforations], NYDA.1986.004.01628
        - [Study of exterior perspective showing a concrete block wall with square perforations], NYDA.1986.004.01629
        - [Study of exterior perspective], NYDA.1986.004.01630
        - [Sketch of north exterior wall with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.01631
        - [Sketch of plan of west porch(?) with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.01632
        - [Sketch of an unidentified elevation with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.01633
        - [Sketch of an isometric view of an unidentified corner and other details, with measurements], NYDA.1986.004.01634
      - Papers
        - archival: (Box A10, Folder 72-2)
          (4 pages of notes, 6 samples (5 asbestos samples.))
        - archival: (Box A10, Folder 72-4)
          (correspondence, receipts, bills, certificates, statements. Corresponded with: Robert D. Howard. Worked with: Kurt Versen Company (lighting), Gustav F. Wild (glass), and others.)
        - archival (Box A10, Folder 72-5)
          (1 sheet found with drawing folder 2: 1 page of notes.)
  - Job 73, Seymour N. Fox
    - [Seymour N. Fox auto back-draft protector (New Canaan, Conn.)]
      - Drawings, #.01635-.01637 October 11, 1940, 3 sheets: various media; or smaller 64.1 x 83.8 cm.; 25-1/4 x 33 inches
        This set consists of 2 pencil on paper and 1 pencil with pastel on tracing paper. The Auto back-draft protector was to be installed in a 1941 Mercury according to archives.
        - Elev., plan, sect., and F.S. details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 10/11/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01635
        - [Sketch of cross section with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.01636
        - [Sketch of details with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.01637
      - Papers
        - archival: (Box A11, Folder 73-2)
          (samples, correspondence, orders, notes, pamphlets. Corresponded with: Seymour N. Fox. Worked with: Rohm & Haas Company (plexiglass), E.I. Du Pont Nemours & Company, and others.)
  - Job 74, Wallace Lenz
    - [Wallace Lanz wallpaper. Design drawings]
      - Drawings, #.01638-.01640 1930s, 3 sheets: various media; or smaller 66.4 x 76.5 cm.; 26-1/8 x 30-1/8 inches
        This set consists of 1 charcoal and pencil on tracing paper, and 2 pastel on tracing paper. Wallace Lanz's address at the time of this project was 286 Fifth Avenue, New York, N.Y., however the archives show no evidence as to where the wallpaper would be applied.
        - [Wallpaper design]. Pastel on tracing paper., NYDA.1986.004.01638
          (This design continues on 1986.004.01639.)
        - [Wallpaper design]. Pastel on tracing paper., NYDA.1986.004.01639
          (This design continues on 1986.004.01638.)
        - [Study for wallpaper design]., NYDA.1986.004.01640; Charcoal on tracing paper. Verso is a pencil with charcoal trace.
  - Job 75, Famaes Realty Co
    - [Famaes Development (Hampton Bays, N.Y.). Houses A, A-1, A-2, B, B-1, C, D, D-1, D-2, and D-3]
      - Drawings, #.01641-.01726, #.02917-.02919 1911-1950, 89 sheets: various media; or smaller 74.9 x 107 cm.; 29-1/2 x 42-1/8 inches
        This set consists of 27 blueprints, 5 blueprints with pastel, 6 blackline prints and 2 stats on paper; and 38 pencil, 8 pencil with pastel, 2 charcoal, and 1 pencil, pastel and ink on tracing paper. he majority of the drawings were produced between January-March 1941. Famaes Development was earlier referred to as Famaes Realty Co. of Pon Quogue, Long Island. Drawing 7 and 7-A (1986.004.02917-.02919) were originally filed with Job 127, Bay Avenue Development (Hampton Bays, N.Y.).
        - House "A": plot plan [and] wall section [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1, 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01641
        - House "A": plot plan, wall section and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 01/27/1941 revised 2/6/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01642
        - House "A": plot plan, wall section and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 01/27/1941 revised, 2/6/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01643; Blueprint on paper.
        - House "A": plot plan, wall section and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1 01/27/1941 revised, 2/6/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01644; Blueprint with pastel on paper.
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01644]., NYDA.1986.004.01645
        - House "A": plot plan, wall section and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1B, 3/12/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01646
        - House "A": plot plan, wall section and details [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 1B 3/12/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01647; Blueprint on paper.
        - House "A": plans [showing cellar and foundation and first floor plans and a door schedule, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2, 1/3/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01648
        - House "A": plans, first fl., cellar and foundation, [and a] door schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2, 1/3/41, revised 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01649
          (Pastel was used on the verso to highlight the image on the recto.)
        - House "A": plans, first fl., cellar, foundation [and a] door schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2, 1/3/41, revised 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01650; Blueprint on paper.
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01650]., NYDA.1986.004.01651
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01650]., NYDA.1986.004.01652
        - House "A": plans, first fl., cellar and foundation, [and a] door schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2B 3/5/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01653
          (Pastel was used on the verso to highlight parts of the image on the recto.)
        - House "A": plans, first fl., cellar, and foundation, [and a] door schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 2B 3/5/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01654; Blueprint on paper.
        - House "A": elevations [of the exterior, and a window schedule, with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3, 1/3/41, revised 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01655
        - House "A": elevations [of exterior and a] window schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3, 1/3/41, revised 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01656
        - House "A": elevations [of exterior and a] window schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3, 1/3/41, revised 1/27/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01657; Blueprint on paper.
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01657]., NYDA.1986.004.01658
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01657]., NYDA.1986.004.01659
        - House "A": elevations [of exteriors and a] window schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3B, 3/5/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01660
        - House "A": elevations [of exteriors and a] window schedule [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 3B 3/5/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01661; Blueprint on paper.
        - House "A, A-1 and A-2": isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and alternative plans [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 1/20/1941 Drawing "4" has been penciled in., NYDA.1986.004.01662
        - House "A, A-1 and A-2": isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and alternative plans [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 1/20/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01663; Blueprint on paper.
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01663]., NYDA.1986.004.01664
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01663]., NYDA.1986.004.01665
        - House "A, A-1 and A-2": isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and alternate plans [including] subdivision [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 01/20/1941 revised 3/12/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01666
        - House "A, A-1 and A-2": isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and alternate plans [including] subdivision [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 4 01/20/1941 revised, 3/12/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01667; Blueprint on paper.
        - House "A" interior elevs. and reflected ceil. plans [showing living rm., kitchen, bath, dining alcove, hall and bedrooms 1 and 2]: Drawing 5, 2/14/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01668
        - House "A" interior elevs. and reflected ceil. plans [showing living rm., kitchen, bath, dining alcove, hall and bedrooms 1 and 2]: Drawing 5 2/14/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01669; Blueprint on paper.
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01669]., NYDA.1986.004.01670
        - House "A": interior elevs. and reflected ceiling plans [showing living rm., kitchen, bath, dining alcove, hall and bedrooms 1 and 2]: Drawing 5B, 3/17/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01671
        - House "A": interior elevs. and reflected ceiling plans [showing living rm., kitchen, bath, dining alcove, hall and bedrooms 1 and 2]: Drawing 5B 3/17/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01672; Blueprint on paper.
        - Houses "B, B-1 and C": isometric [i.e. axonometric] view and alternate plans: Drawing 6, 3/4/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01673
        - House "D": preliminary plan and isometric [i.e. axonometric] view [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 7, 3/7/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02917
        - House "D": preliminary plan and isometric [i.e. axonometric] view [with notes and measurements]: Drawing 7 3/7/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02918; Blueprint on paper.
        - Houses "D-1, D-2, and D-3": preliminary alternate plans: Drawing 7A, 3/8/1950, NYDA.1986.004.01674
        - Houses "D-1, D-2 and D-3": preliminary alternate plans: Drawing 7A 3/8/1950, NYDA.1986.004.02919; Blueprint on paper.
        - Map of land belonging to Mary M. Horton situate at Good Ground, Suffolk County, N.Y. / James A.S. Gregg, Surveyor, April 1911., NYDA.1986.004.01675
          (Verso notes "Horton Property".)
        - Map of property owned by Famaes Realty Company situate Pon Quogue, town of Southampton, Long Island, N.Y. / Wallace H. Halsey, C.E., February 13, 1930. Stat., NYDA.1986.004.01681
        - Map of property owned by Famaes Realty Company situate Pon Quogue, town of Southampton, Long Island, N.Y. / Wallace H. Halsey, C.E., February 13, 1930., NYDA.1986.004.01682; Stat with negative ground.
        - Subdivision map, property of F.A. Muschenheim, situate Hampton Bays, Long Island, N.Y. [showing a U.S. Geological Survey of Riverhead Quadrangle, a key map, a plat map, a typical layout of well and cesspool, and a plan and sectional elevation of a typical leaching cesspool [with notes]: A 8021-1074 / Theodore F. Squires, Licensed Land Surveyor No. 15683 March 12, 1941, NYDA.1986.004.01676
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01676]., NYDA.1986.004.01677
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01676]., NYDA.1986.004.01678
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01676]., NYDA.1986.004.01679
        - [Duplicate copy of 1986.004.01676]., NYDA.1986.004.01680
        - [Plat map showing subdivision of Famaes Realty Co.]., NYDA.1986.004.01683
        - [Plat map showing preliminary lay-out of site for Famaes Realty Co.]., NYDA.1986.004.01684
        - [Plat map showing preliminary lay-out of site for Famaes Realty Co.]., NYDA.1986.004.01685; Blueprint on paper.
        - [Axonometric views of house type "C" and "B"(?) and a partial view of type "A"]., NYDA.1986.004.01686
        - [House "A-1": study of axonometric view]., NYDA.1986.004.01687
        - [House "A-1": study of exterior perspective]., NYDA.1986.004.01688
        - [Study of unidentified interior perspective showing corner windows]., NYDA.1986.004.01689
        - [House "A": study of exterior elevation, garden side, with measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.01690
        - [House "A": study of exterior elevation, garden side]., NYDA.1986.004.01691
        - [House "A": study of exterior elevation, yard side]., NYDA.1986.004.01692
        - [House "A-2"(?): study of exterior elevation, door at far left, garden side]., NYDA.1986.004.01693
        - [House "A-2"(?): study of exterior elevation, garden side]., NYDA.1986.004.01694
        - [House "A-2": study of exterior elevation, yard side]., NYDA.1986.004.01695
        - [House "B"(?): study of exterior elevation]., NYDA.1986.004.01696
        - [House "B"(?): study of exterior elevation, showing front(?) entrance]., NYDA.1986.004.01697
        - [Sketch of unidentified partial elevation]., NYDA.1986.004.01698
        - House "A": study [of] plan and [exterior] elevations 12/14/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01699
          (This has also been shown as House "A-2".)
        - [House "A-2": study of exterior elevations and a plan with notes]., NYDA.1986.004.01700
        - [House "B-1": study of exterior elevations and a plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01701
        - [House "C": study of exterior elevations and plans]., NYDA.1986.004.01702
        - House "A": plans [of 1st floor and garage, with notes and measurements], 1/3/1941, NYDA.1986.004.01703
        - [House "A": study of plan showing house and partial garage, with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01704
        - [House "A": study of plan showing layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01705
        - [House "A": study of plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01706
        - [House "A-2": study of plan and partial of (?) showing layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01707
        - [House "A-2": study of plan with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01708
        - [House "A-2": study of plan with layout]. Charcoal on tracing paper., NYDA.1986.004.01709
        - House "A" (alternates): study of plans A-2 and A-3 12/14/1940, NYDA.1986.004.01710
        - [House "A-3"(?): sketch of plan with stairs]., NYDA.1986.004.01711
        - [House "A-3": sketch of plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01712
        - [House "B"(?): study of plan showing table and chairs]., NYDA.1986.004.01713
        - [House "B"(?): study of plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01714
        - [House "B-1": study of plan with layout]., NYDA.1986.004.01715
        - [House "B-1": study of plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01716
        - [House "D"(?): study of plan including garage]., NYDA.1986.004.01717
        - [House "D"(?): studies of 3 different plans]., NYDA.1986.004.01718
        - [House "D"(?): study of plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01719
        - [Garage: study of plan and details with notes and measurements]., NYDA.1986.004.01720
        - [Sketches of numbered furniture showing isometric and perspective views of tables, a stool, book shelf, and chest of drawers]., NYDA.1986.004.01721
          (Drawing is matted on a sheet of white paper and black construction paper.)
        - [Sketch of unidentified plan regarding plumbing with notes]., NYDA.1986.004.01722
        - [Plan showing excavation plan and section showing leaching chamber of liquefying tank(?), with notes and measurements] / Aten Sewage Disposal Co., Inc., NYDA.1986.004.01723
        - Construction drawings [showing an isometric view of the tank excavation and section of the placing form, with notes] / Aten Sewage Disposal Co., NYDA.1986.004.01724
        - Liquefying tank [showing excavation plan and section with notes and measurements] / Aten Sewage Disposal Co., NYDA.1986.004.01725
        - [Light fixture Type T1-115, showing elevations and perspective view, with notes and measurements]: #4110-91 / Kurt Versen, Inc., NYDA.1986.004.01726
      - Papers
        - archival: specifications. (Box A11, Folder 75-10)
        - archival: specifications. (Box A11, Folder 75-11)
        - archival: specifications, and related material. (Box A11, Folder 75-12)
        - archival: estimates. (Box A11, Folder 75-13)
        - archival: (Box A11, Folder 75-14)
          (notes, clippings, pamphlet, and material related to chairs and other furniture.)
        - archival: correspondence, notes, bulletins. (Box A11, Folder 75-15)
          (Corresponded with: South Lumber Corporation, E.W. Howell Co. (builders), W.A. Case & Son Mfg. Co., NY Department of Health, Fred A. Muschenheim, Theodore F. Squires (land surveyor), Robert J. Michaelsen, Clarence M. Carman (contractor and builder), and others.)
  - Job 76, Rudolph Serkin
    - Rudolph Serkin 1940
      - Papers
        - archival: (Box A11, Folder 76-11)
          (1 order, 3 items of correspondence. Worked with: Protection Specialties Corp.)
  - Job 77, Hoyt and Page
    - [Office building on Lot #291, bounded by 13th Street, Pennsylvania Avenue, "E" Street and 12th Street, Washington, D.C.]
      [Aviation Building and Union Air Station (Washington, D.C.) Plats]
      - Drawings, #.01727 January 1941, 1 drawings pencil with pastel on tracing paper; or smaller 22.9 x 19.7 cm.; 9 x 7-3/4 inches
        (File 77 also contained information on Lot #379 and the Meridian Hill Park area of Washington, D.C., which were catalogued separately. These projects never developed into commissions. The building contract was drawn between Muschenheim and Aviation Building Corporation, National Press Building, Washington, D.C. Muschenheim's address was 140 East 39th Street, New York, N.Y. at the time of this project.)
        - Drawing, January 1941, NYDA.1986.004.01727
      - Papers
        - archival: (Box A11, Folder 77-2)
          (1 preliminary study for the Aviation Building Union Air Station, 10 pp. not including blue prints at end.)
        - archival: (Box A11, Folder 77-3)
          (1 page of notes, 1 map of Washington, D.C.)
        - archival: correspondence, agreements. (Box A11, Folder 77-4)
          (Corresponded with: Celeste Page (Hoyt & Page), and others.)
    - [Office building on Lot #379, bounded by 10th Street, Pennsylvania Avenue, "D" Street and 9th Street, Washington, D.C.] [graphic]: [studies of plats].
      [Office building, Lot #379 (Washington, D.C.) Plats]
      - Drawings, #.01728-.01729 January 1941, 2 drawings pencil on tracing paper; or smaller 45.6 x 37.8 cm.; 18 x 14-7/8 inches
        (The building contract was drawn between Muschenheim and Franklin Square Building Corporation.)
        - [Sketch of site plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01728
        - [Study of plat map].s, NYDA.1986.004.01729
    - [Meridian Hill Park area (Washington, D.C.). Plats]
      - Drawings, #.01730-.01731 1941, 2 sheets 26.5 x 30.2 cm.; 10-3/8 x 11-7/8 inches
        This set consists of 1 pencil on paper and 1 blueprint on paper.
        - [Sketch of site plan]., NYDA.1986.004.01730
        - [Study of plat map]., NYDA.1986.004.01731
  - Job 78, Furniture Company
    - [Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.). Industrial Design Competition. Competition drawings]
      - Drawings #.01732-.01754 1941, 23 sheets 68 x 93 cm.; 26-3/4 x 36-5/8 inches
        This set consists of 18 charcoal on tracing paper, 1 charcoal and pastel on tracing paper, 3 pencil on tracing paper, and 1 pencil on paper. This competition closed January 11, 1941.
        - [Study of an interior perspective showing desk and shelves]., NYDA.1986.004.01732
        - [Study of an axonometric view of a built-in desk and shelves]., NYDA.1986.004.01733
        - [Isometric study of a cushioned chair with bentwood(?) arm rests/side supports and a separate base support under the seat]., NYDA.1986.004.01734
        - [Isometric study of a cushioned chair with an armrest of bentwood(?) continuing into front supports and terminating as rear supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01735
        - [Study of a plan and front and side elevations showing a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01736
        - [Study of a side elevation of a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports, and a sketch of another side elevation of a chair]., NYDA.1986.004.01737
        - [Study of a side elevation of a reclining chair with a textured cushion and bentwood(?) supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01738
        - [Study of a side elevation of a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports]. Charcoal with pastel on tracing paper., NYDA.1986.004.01739
        - [Study of a side elevation of a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01740
        - [Study of a front elevation of a chair with cushions, and an unidentified sketch]., NYDA.1986.004.01741
        - [Study of a rear elevation of a chair showing cushion supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01742
        - [Isometric study of a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01743; Pencil on tracing paper.
        - [Isometric study of a reclining chair with bentwood(?) supports]., NYDA.1986.004.01744
        - [Isometric study of a bentwood(?) supported reclining chair]., NYDA.1986.004.01745